US/CA Citizen Vancouver, BC, CA egoullaud@gmail.com

LEE GOULLAUD

Full Stack Developer

GitHub Linkedin Portfolio

I'm a full stack developer with 1.5 years of experience working with React, Tailwind, Node and Python. You can view samples of my work as a freelance developer here and here and <a href="https://examples.orgivity.com/here. I am a UX Design and Front End Bootcamp graduate and created a free bootcamp for Front End Developers transitioning to Full Stack. In addition to my freelance work, I am a lead full stack developer with Chingu, building an application using Agile methologies within an asynchronous team environment.

SKILLS:

Languages & Frameworks - JavaScript, Python, ASP.NET, React, Express, Node, Next, GraphQL, SQL, HTML, CSS, Git, Jest Databases - Firebase, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Cloudinary, headless CMS(Contentful, Hygraph)

Libraries - Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI, MapBox, Apollo, Axios, GraphQL-Request, Figma

Other - TDD, agile methdology, cloud platforms, UX design, web accessibility, REST APIs, GitHub, Visual Studio Code, Vercel, Netlify, Slack, Linux

Soft Skills - Collaborative, 7+ years leadership experience, positive, reliable, adapable, willingness to learn, takes inititaive, wears mutlple hats, conflict resolution

RECENT PROJECTS:

Raine Gauthier Photography React | Next | Tailwind | Firebase | GraphQL | Hygraph/Cloudinary | Vercel

April 2023

- Redesigned website from basic JS/HTML/CSS to Next/React/Tailwind with Hygraph headless CMS
- Authentication and authorization for client log in with Firebase
- Dashboard feature for uploading photos to Cloudinary and editing Galleries with drag and drop capability.

Sixpo: Non-Profit

React | Next | Tailwind | GraphQL | Hygraph | Vercel | Figma

Dec 2022 - April 2023

- Website built for a non-profit, SIXpo Sexuality, Inclusion, and Exploration for their online and in person educational festival for disabled folks. Site utilizes dynamic routing, live updates to event schedule, filtered resources and blog posts.
- Collaborated with non-profit employees to ensure accessibility, increasing site engagement by 90%.
- Received positive feedback and appreciation, including partner organizations, resulting in 3 referrals.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Lead Full Stack Developer

Chingu

April 2023-Present

- Facilitated regular paired programming sessions using React, Next.js, Node.js and Tailwind to improve team productivity and coding skills
- Coordinated Agile sprint meetings and provided technical support to junior developers resulting in successful project delivery
- Produced high-quality Figma mock-ups that were instrumental in the design of our applications
- Contributed to organizing file structure for application and built out higher-level JavaScript/React components improving code readability and maintainability

Full Stack Developer Freelance

Jun 2022- Present

- Designed, developed, and maintained 4 full stack websites, including an accessible website for a charity festival for disabled individuals.
- Achieved a 75% increase in user engagement on completed websites.
- Implemented headless CMS to streamline event tracking, speaker information, and blog post updates, resulting in a 75% reduction in client workload.
- Practiced Agile methodology with weekly sprints, continuous deployment, and code reviews to ensure efficient project delivery.

Business Owner Flowers by Elizabeth Feb 2015 - April 2022

- I collaborated with clients and community stakeholders to design and build sustainable gardens, while providing education on organic gardening practices through workshops and resources.
- Demonstrated outstanding leadership, storytelling, and public speaking skills to promote sustainable garden practices and build strong client relationships.
- Utilized effective time management and collaborative problem-solving to manage projects, train and mentor staff, and work effectively with cross-functional teams.

US/CA Citizen Vancouver, BC, CA egoullaud@gmail.com

LEE GOULLAUD

Full Stack Developer

GitHub Linkedin Portfolio

REFERENCES: recommendations available <u>here</u>. Contact information available upon request

Murray Meehan, Senior Software Developer at Microsoft

Alison Lee, Software Developer at LionApp

Calico Seders, Full Stack Developer at SingleOps

Anne Katzeff, Front End Developer and UX Designer

DEGREES & CERTIFICATIONS

Scrum Fundamentals Certification, ScrumStudy – Accreditation Body for Scrum and Agile Certification Front End Development and UX Design, SkillCrush Bootcamp BSc Natural Resource Conservation, University of British Columbia

May 2023 Mar 2022-Sep 2022

AWARDS:

Second Place Winner - Strolls: a Walking Adventure, Girl Develop It Hackathon

Nov 2022

2012-2018

PUBLICATIONS:

<u>Predation risk-induced adjustments in provisioning behavior for Horned Lark (Eremophila alpestris)</u>

Mar 2018

in British Columbia, Wilson Journal of Ornithology

LANGUAGES

Mandarin Chinese - conversational

English - native speaker